Guide to the Records of The New York Institute for the Humanities RG 37.4
New York University Archives
Records of the New York Institute for the Humanities
Bulk, 1980-1984
1971-2004
RG 37.4
New York University Archives
20.5 linear feet
The Records of the New York Institute of the Humanities consist of materials created by the Institute's founder Richard Sennett, and other Institute adminstrators and Fellows. The Records document the formation and early years of the Institute, the activities of Institute Fellows, and the seminars, lectures, and other events sponsored by the Institute.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title and then in reverse chronology within each folder. Audio tapes are generally arranged chronologically, although tapes received in later accessions are not in chronological order.
The records are grouped into 3 series:
Director's Files
Seminars, Lectures, and Events
Audio Recordings
Scope and Content Note
The Records of the New York Institute for the Humanities collection offers unique access for researchers interested in the history of intellectual life and the humanities in the period between 1975 and 1985. While the Institute’s mission focused on intellectual activity in New York City, it also brought noted intellectuals to New York from Latin America and Europe, including those supported by the Exiled Writers program.
In addition to materials relating to the operation and activities of the Institute, the collection contains a large number of documents generated by Professor Richard Sennett, founder and former Director of the Institute.
Series I: Director’s Files: This series consists of records generated by the Director’s Office and its staff. These records are related to both the administration of the Institute as well as non-Institute matters associated with the professional career of the Director. Richard Sennett generated the majority of the documents in this series; many of these relate to his career as an academic and a writer outside of his capacity as Director, such as correspondence with publishers and conference organizers.
Series I is broken up into four Subseries:
A. Administrative
B. Individuals
C. Institutions
D. Subject Files
Series II: Seminars, Lectures and Events: This series consists of records generated in the course of organizing and administering internal and public events; these materials include correspondence, reading lists, seminar minutes, posters, and transcripts of talks. Institute seminar leaders and members created many of the documents in this series. Materials for each seminar can range from one page of information, such as a list of attendees, to multiple folders of documents, sometimes including summary notes from each session and reading packets. Materials relating to Institute events, such as public lectures, include correspondence, transcripts of lectures and discussions, guest lists, and advertising flyers.
Significant seminars include Thomas Bender and William Taylor’s “Culture of Cities”, Richard Sennett and Michel Foucault’s “Sexuality and Solitude”, and the seminar “Sexuality, Gender and Consumer Culture”. The year-long Times Square Conferences which evolved into the book “Inventing Times Square” (1991) are also well-documented.
A List of all seminars and lectures held at the Institute between its founding and 1987 can be found in the Institute’s Ten Year Report (Series I.A: Box 3 Folder 13).
The last box in this series consists of student recommendation files created by Richard Sennett. Access to these student records are limited by FERPA, and the materials are restricted.
Series III: Audio Recordings: Not all audio recordings of Institute events have been digitized for research use. Please contact the University Archives with questions about materials available digitally. Additionally, some of the recordings were previously transcribed, and those transcriptions are contained in Series II.
The audio recordings are divided into three subseries:
A: Cassette Tapes
B: 1/4 Inch Reels
C: Mini Disks
History of the New York Institute for the Humanities
In the summer of 1976, New York University Professor of Sociology Richard Sennett chaired a conference on the Humanities and Social Thought in Bellagio, Italy. Sennett and other participants developed the idea for a New York-based institute to foster intellectual discourse and cross-disciplinary communication while at the conference. In December 1976 New York University and Richard Sennett’s Center for Humanistic Studies co-sponsored the conference “The Future of the Intellectual Community in New York”, which was co-organized by Sennett, New York University President John Sawhill, and New York University Professor Ronald Florence (then Director of the New York Council for the Humanities). Based on the success of the conference, Richard Sennett and President Sawhill co-hosted a series of informal dinners for cultural, labor, and business leaders, writers, and artists. Participants discussed how to continue to redefine and strengthen intellectual life in New York City. The ideas that arose from the dinners provided the structure for the New York Institute for the Humanities. Correspondence about these dinners, and the first proposals for a New York Institute for the Humanities, can be found in the Administrative Papers of President John Crittenden Sawhill (RG 3.0.8), Box 44.
In 1977 the New York Institute for the Humanities was established as a permanent activity of New York University by an act of the university’s Board of Trustees. An advisory board was formed to help with the Institute’s early development, while Sennett, New York Times editor Caroline Rand Herron, and New York University Humanities Professor Thomas Bender worked with administrative assistant Toni Greenberg on the Institute’s day-to-day operations. Rand Herron acted as a publications and communications consultant, creating a series of Institute lunches and Public Forums. Bender also contributed considerable time and organized the Institute’s first Gallatin Lectures. In 1978, the Institute received significant funding from the Exxon Education Foundation and the National Endowment for the Humanities, enabling expansion of its Fellowship and Lecture activities. In 1980 the Institute was independently incorporated and formed its own Board of Trustees; however, all daily administrative activities were handled by New York University, with the Institute’s Board serving primarily in an advisory role.
From the time of the Institute’s inception, the Fellowship program was the core of the New York Institute for the Humanities, embodying its mission to support the work of individual scholars and intellectuals in an environment which encouraged interaction. About half of the early fellows were academics from New York-area universities, while the rest were artists, writers, journalists, and public officials. In the early years, fellows generally met once or twice a month for informal seminars. As the Institute grew, Sennett worked with Aryeh Neier and Thomas Bender to create a more defined program in which Fellows--elected to either one-year or five-year fellowships--formed interdisciplinary seminars around topics of interest and participated in weekly Fellows Lunches. Most Fellows were unpaid, although some received office space or clerical support. Fellows were responsible for the Institute’s internal operations, which were overseen by the Director and three committees: an Executive Committee, a Program Committee, and a Fellowship Selection Committee.
The Program Committee was particularly active during the Institute’s first five years. The Institute hosted public lecture series and conferences, most notably the James Lecture Series and the Gallatin Lecture Series. In a concerted move to counter American isolationist tendencies at the time, the James Lectures brought primarily European intellectuals to the Institute. The Gallatin Lecture Series was created shortly thereafter to provide a diverse public audience for American humanists. The period of 1979-1983 was especially active, bringing such literary and intellectual figures as Michel Foucault, Italo Calvino, Czeslow Milosz, Jorge Luis Borges and Roland Barthes to speak publicly and to participate in seminars. In 1981 the Institute launched a Humanities Exchange Program for writers exiled from Latin American and Eastern European regimes. Many of the Institute’s early lectures were published by Columbia University Press in “Humanities in Review” (1982), edited by David Rieff.
The Institute is still in operation, currently comprising approximately 150 Fellows, and typically holds luncheon-lectures for Institute Fellows every Friday of the academic year. In addition the NYIH organizes a variety of seminars, conferences, discussions, readings and performances that are free and open to the public.
Only a partial list of Directors of the Institute has been confirmed:
1977-78 - Richard Sennett
1978-79 - Richard Sennett and Thomas Bender
1979-80 - Loren Baritz
1980-81 - Aryeh Neier
1981-82 - Edmund White
1982-83 - Edmund White
1983-84 - Edmund White and Richard Sennett
1984-85 - Jerome Bruner
1986-87 - William R. Taylor and A. Richard Turner
1987-88 - A. Richard Turner
As founder of the Institute, Richard Sennett’s papers form a large part of this collection. Sennett, an interdisciplinary scholar, novelist, and social critic, is currently Professor of History and Sociology at New York University, and Professor of Sociology and Chair of the Cities Programme at the London School of Economics. Born in Chicago in 1943, Sennett was trained as a cellist at the Julliard School of Music, and later studied sociology at Harvard University. After brief appointments at Yale and Brandeis Universities, he came to New York University in 1972, where he has spent the majority of his career. Sennett has written over a dozen books on subjects ranging from urbanism to modern capitalism, including The Hidden Injuries of Class (1972), The Fall of Public Man (1976), and Authority, as well as the novel The Frog Who Dared to Croak (1982).
Sources:
Benn, Melissa “Inner City Scholar” The Guardian Saturday February 3, 2001
Rieff, David. Humanities in Review Cambridge: New York Institute for the Humanities, 1982
Administrative Papers of President John Crittenden Sawhill, 1974-1981, (RG 3.0.8) New York University Archives
Access Restrictions
The majority of the files are open for research without restrictions, although University administrative records are closed for 20 years from the date of creation. Access to student records is limited by FERPA. Specific information relating to applications and appointments is also restricted.
This collection is in
off-site storage
.
Provenance
The bulk of the materials were transferred from the New York Institute for the Humanties to the University Archives in 2002. An additional transfer of audio recordings was made in 2007.
Baritz, Loren, 1928-; Bender, Thomas; Borges, Jorge Luis, 1899-1986; Breytenbach, Breyten; Brodsky, Joseph, 1940-1996; Calvino, Italo; Derrida, Jacques; Dorsen, Norman; FitzGerald, Frances, 1940-; Foucault, Michel, 1926-1984; Geertz, Clifford; Gitlin, Todd; Glass, Philip; Gordimer, Nadine; Habermas, Jürgen; Hampshire, Stuart; Haskell, Francis, 1928-; Hobsbawm, E. J., (Eric J.), 1917-; Huxtable, Ada Louise; Kamm, F. M., (Frances Myrna); Kapuściński, Ryszard, 1932-2007; Kos, Danilo, 1935-1989; Menuhin, Yehudi, 1916-1999; Milosz, Czesław; Moravia, Alberto, 1907-1990; Naipaul, V. S., (Vidiadhar Surajprasad), 1932-; Neier, Aryeh, 1937-; Nochlin, Linda; Orlov, Yuri, 1924-; Poirier, Richard; Reich, Steve, 1936-; Rieff, David; Rorty, Richard; Rubert de Ventós, Xavier; Sacks, Oliver W.; Safdie, Moshe, 1938-; Sass, Louis Arnorsson; Sassen, Saskia; Sawhill, John C., 1936-; Schorske, Carl E.; Sennett, Richard, 1943-; Sieburth, Richard; Snitow, Ann Barr, 1943-; Sontag, Susan, 1933-2004; Spender, Stephen, 1909-1995; Turkel, Gerald; Turner, Richard, 1932-; Varnedoe, Kirk, 1946-2003; Voinovich, Vladimir, 1932-; Wahl, Nicholas; Ward, Eileen; White, Edmund, 1940-; Wittig, Monique
- Series I: Director's Files
  - Subseries A: Administrative
    - Accounting Problems, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      barcode#:31142042273188
    - Accounting Problems, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Action Memos, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Advisory Board, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Advisory Board, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Apartment Rental, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors - Bakstansky, Peter, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors - Golden, William T., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors - Rose, Daniel, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors - Smith, Roger R., undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors - Soros, George, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Board of Trustees - By-Laws, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Board of Trustees - Fund-Raising, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Board of Trustees - General, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Board of Trustees - General, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042273196
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Dec 5, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Apr 7, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Jul 28, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Nov 4, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Jan 15, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Apr 8, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Sep 28, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Oct 28, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Jan 11, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Apr 5, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Nov 4, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, Feb 16, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Board of Trustees - Meeting, May 16, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Board of Trustees - Piel, George, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Board of Trustees - Simmons, Richard D., undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Board of Trustees - Straus, Roger, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Brochure, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Budget, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - By-Laws, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Consortium - Columbia University, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Consortium - Graduate Center of the CUNY, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Consortium - Hunter College, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Corporate Campaign, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Culture in New York City Fellowship Program, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Doctoral Consortium in the Humanities and Social Thought Proposal, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Early Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Executive Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042273204
    - Fellowship Applications, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Fellowship Applications, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Invitations to Fellows, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Mailing List, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - New York University - Central Administration, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - New York University - NYIH Relationship, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Report to the Special Committee on the New York Institute for the Humanities, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Ten-Year Report, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Subseries B: Individuals
    - Joann Akalaitis, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Quentin Anderson, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Lord Noel Annan, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Antonella Antonelli, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Jennifer Bartlett, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042273212
    - Francois Bedarida, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Thomas Bender, 1976-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Jessica Benjamin, 1978-1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Ivan Bennett, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Isaiah Berlin, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Reinhard Bendix, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Paul Berman, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Jeremy Bernstein, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Yvette Biro, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Thomas Bishop, 1977-1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Jean Carey Bond, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Thomas Bottomore, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Leon Botstein, 1977-1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Pierre Bourdieu, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - John Brademas, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Michael Brock, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Jerome Bruner, 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Jerome Bruner Correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Peter Buckley, 1980-1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Sarah Caldwell, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      barcode#:31142042273220
    - Arnulf Conradi, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Jill Sanchia Cowen, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Vincent Crapanzano, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Norman Dorsen, 1985-1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Denis Donoghue, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - E.L. Doctorow, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Peggy C. Davis, 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Morris Dickstein, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Joseph D. Duffey, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Barbara Ehrenreich, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Carol Feldman, 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Frances Fitzgerald, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Lukas Foss, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Diane Foster, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Terry Freiberg, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - F.G. Friedman, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Robert Geddess, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Clifford Geertz, 1972-1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Faye Ginsburg, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Ruth Goetz, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Vartan Gregorian, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - John Guare, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Charles Halpern, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Agnes Heller, 1979-1984 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Janet Hobhouse, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Eric Hobsbawm, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Klaus Hoffer, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - John Hollander, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Elizabeth Holtzman, 1983-1986 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Ada Louise Huxtable, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Temma Kaplan, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Alice Kessler Harris, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - George Konrad (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - William Leach, 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042273238
    - Serge Le Claire, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Wassily Leontief, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Michael Massing, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Paul Mattick, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Humberto Maturana, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Russell Meares, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Czeslaw Milosz ( New Yorker), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Arnaldo Momigliano, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Senator Daniel Patrick Moynihan, 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Anthony Movshon, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Thea Musgrave, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - V.S. Naipaul, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Aryeh Neier, 1975-1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Dorothy Nelkin, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Linda Nochlin, 1982-1989 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Yuri Orlov, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - C. Duncan Rice, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - David Richards, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - David Rieff, 1979-1984 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Edward Rothstein, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Elisabeth Ruge, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042273246
    - Oliver W. Sacks, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Saskia Sassen-Koob, 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Louis A. Sass, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Richard Schechner, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Paul Schmidt, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Carl E. Schorske, 1980-1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Joan C. Schwartz, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Richard Sennett, 1978-1985 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Richard Sennett - Engagements, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Theda Skocpol, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Ann Barr Snitow, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Susan Sontag, 1979-1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Stephen and Natasha Spender, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Richard Stamelman, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Nikos Stangos, 1976-1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Domna Stanton, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Jean Starobinski, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Roger Straus, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Pep Subiros, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - William Taylor, 1979-1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042273253
    - Gerald M. Turkel, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - A. Richard Turner, 1982-1986 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - A. Richard Turner Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Brian Urquhart, 1982-1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Luisa Valenzuela, 1979-1981 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Kirk Varnedoe, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Xavier Rubert De Ventos, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Ileana Verzea, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Nicholas Wahl, 1979-1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Eric Wanner, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Aileen Ward, 1979-1988 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Ann Warnford-Davis, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Annette Weiner, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Monique Wittig - Dossier, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - K.D. Wolff, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Gwendolyn Wright, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Carol Yaple, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Subseries C: Institutions
    - AAAS - Denver, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - AAAS - Publications, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - All Souls, Oxford, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - American Academy in Rome, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - American Sociological Association, 1977-1981 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Architectural Association (London), 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - ASA Meetings, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Aspen Institute, 1977-1983 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1981-1984 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      barcode#:31142042273261
    - Australian Broadcasting Commission, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Author's Guild, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Bard College, 1979-1984 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - British Sociological Association, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Cambridge University, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Cambridge University Press (Cambridge), 1976-1981 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Cambridge University Press (New York), 1980-1985 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Jocelyn Carlson, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Center for Urban Affairs, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Century Club, 1979-1984 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Collège de France, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Columbia University, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Columbia University Press, 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Corporate Architecture Group, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Eastern Sociological Society, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Ecole des Hautes Etudes, 1976-1981 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Editions du Seuil, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Editions Recherches, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Editorial Kairós, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Esprit, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Faber and Faber, 1979-1986 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Farrar, Straus & Giroux Inc., 1979-1984 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Fayard, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Feltrinelli Edetore, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Ford Foundation, 1974-1984 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - The French-America Foundation, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Paul and Peter Fritz AG, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Geo Magazine, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - David R. Goldine, Inc., 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Granada Television International, Ltd., 1979 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Hardy Holzman Pfeiffer Associates, undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Harper's, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 36)